NICOLAS CHANG

SR FRONT-END ENGINEER

Javascript | React | Angular | Typescript | Node | GraphQL | AWS

nicolaschana199@amail.com

Phone +1 626 467 3805 **Address**

1340 Pasqualito Dr. San marino, CA



English

Korean

Chinese

Summary

A Front-End Engineer who has been working as a professional web developer for more than

10years, most proficient at front-end development using Javascript.

Produced optimized, user-friendly web pages using React, Angular, and Typescript.

Influenced full-stack and back-end development and often managed leadership roles as well.

Using **MERN** and **MEAN** stack, completed 5+ projects alone.

In addition, have relevant experience in making smart contract and experienced **Defi** and **NFT**.

However, heavily focused on the frontend part particularly using JS frameworks and libraries.

The strongest skills are

Javascript / React / Angular/ Node / Typescript / GraphQL / AWS.

Education

2008 - 2011

Minnan University of Science and Technology

- Bachelor's degree in Computer Science
- Studied web development and walked through online courses

Skill set

- Javascript(ES6)
- MongoDB
- Typescript
- Postgresql
- React
- Graphql
- Angular
- Solidity
- Redux
- Web3.js
- Jest
- AWS
- Node
- Azure
- Express
- Git
- Laravel
- Dokcer
- Mysql
- WebSocket

Work experience

Jan 2020 - Mar 2022 Front-End Software Engineer

Velog, Seoul (**Remote**)

- Developed new user-facing features using modern JS frameworks and libraries React.js and Angular
- Completed plan, design, build and implement the user interface in almost **5 large projects**
- Worked with Redux to manage the global states and Redux-Saga to control the redux store
- Built almost **100 reusable components** and front-end libraries for future use
- In **4+ projects**, introduced the correct library and algorithm to reduce the page load time by **70%**
- Facilitated 8 ongoing projects and speed up by nearly 80% than before
- Optimized components for **100% maximum performance** across a vast array of web-capable devices and browsers
- Collaborated together with an engineering team, a designer, and a project manager to achieve the goals of the application, then led to a 40% increase in productivity
- Improved the process that resulted in a 20hour time saving per week that saved **\$10K cost**
- Provided help and guidance to 4 junior developers on the project
- Experienced leadership in **3 medium-size** eCommerce projects leading the engineering team
- Led and launched a big e-commerce project which received 20K unique hits and also 1000 paying clients in 2 weeks

Nov 2014 - Dec 2019 Front-End Developer

A4SAFE, Stafford

- Implemented a 90+ satisfactory user experience with no issues, errors, or downtime
- Created and optimized systems played an active role in testing and troubleshooting, and increased accessibility and browser compatibility by 40%
- Often served as an intermediary bridging the gap between the user and the backend developers, and tweaked 3 tools and platforms to adapt to real-world use situations
- Reviewed code and once upon a time, reduced the amount of code by 25,000 lines
- Organized **20+ high-resolution** mock-ups to test interfaces with
- Finished 5+ small projects alone using **MERN** or **MEAN** stack for faster **cross-platform** development

Nov 2011 - Nov 2014 Full Stack Developer

CoreLogic, Los Angeles

- Influenced in both front-end and back-end for 20+ website applications
- Set servers and databases functionalities to reduce the request time by 30% using PHP
- Ensured 100% cross-platform optimization for both mobile phones and websites
- Ensured responsiveness, rich user experience, and great user interface of applications
- Designed and constructed APIs and cut down the request handling time by 20%
- Stayed abreast of developments in web applications and **5**+ programming languages